[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
[Music]
[Applause]
Tesla on today's episode of the AI
native Dev joining me is Filipe agir
welome welcome Filipe thanks Simon for
having me and today we're going to be
really talking about how you can
generate uh code using projects using
specs using prompts and we're going to
do it in a very developer focused way
exactly where we're going to talk about
it in this episode in a very developer
focused way to show how you can actually
build through discussion through a chat
API and really show what in this case
Claude which is what we're going to be
using to generate that can do we're
going to split this up into two episod
again in this episodes we're just going
to really talk about some of your
experiences what you built using Claude
and then in the next episode which will
be released shortly after this one on
YouTube only we're going to jump into
screen share and we're actually going to
try and build a front end to a database
access let me introduce you Filipe so
Filipe is a senior data scientist you
have a PhD in computer science 15 years
of experience in education research also
startups and government also the
organizer of AI tinkerers which is
actually a worldwide organization they
have chapters effectively in various
places and and whereabouts is your
chapter in medin in colia from Colombia
yeah amazing and so tell us a little bit
about what the AI tinkerers does what it
is as a community sure yeah so AI
thinkers is is a global community and
the idea is we always say the luck is a
mixture between preparation and
opportunity and I always say that AI
thinkers is is the venue where we make
these opportunities happen oh nice you
know so when we bring prepare people
together so that the opportunities can
happen so we gather once a month for
thinkering discussing what we're doing
we have a very relaxed format of
presentation we don't like long format
presentation with slides we just want to
see your code running even if it's messy
it doesn't matter as if you were
bragging what you've done to your best
you know and that really creates a nice
atmosphere so do check that out and see
if there's see if there's there's
chapters all over the world yeah you
mentioned one in lond so I'm definely
check that out I was in Paris last week
for the inauguration yeah yeah yeah cool
and and you're also recently co-founded
a company you're founder as well exactly
yeah I I run a company for two years we
were three co-founders in the fashion
industry it was a blast it was a great
experience a great learning experience
for me and I really got the taste of
Entrepreneurship grinding and working
hard and trying to make things happen uh
but sadly yeah the market is quite hard
at the moment as you can imagine like we
all know that it's quite hard to raise
money at the moment yeah and we did
build a product that even though adds a
lot of value is a really high cost of
acquisition for customer so yeah finally
we didn't make and we decided to make
the right choice which is shutting down
the company yeah I'm sorry to hear that
but as part of that you actually did
some building using projects and
building applications and front ends
with AI so it's not a core part of the
business but you were using it
effectively as a developer I think that
the way we built our company was the
right way to do it two years ago
but what I've learned with yeah with all
of the experience that I've done so far
is that actually it's it's much easier
nowadays to build MVPs I don't know
about production ready products I think
I will still rely on professional
developers to make sure that my front
end is really working I'm not a front
end developer but when I compare the
time it took us to to build the first
prototype the first MVP to show to our
clients to see if they're actually
willing to pay I'm willing to buy this
product versus what I can do today uh
that's incredible like I see that that
this is really going to shape the
industry in serious ways yeah yeah so
let's talk about your journey as it were
through using various different types of
AI in terms of using an AI assistant in
an ID doing one line at a time I guess
co-pilot is most familiar to people for
that type of AI coding
assistant how much have you used that
was it how did you find it yeah like I I
do remember I was part of a private beta
of GitHub co-pilot it was long time ago
I don't remember three four years ago
something like that yeah and I was so
excited I remember talking to my
colleagues back the day I was a
different company people were a bit
hesitant I saw I said like huh this is
actually not that bad like it really
managed to like you started the function
you do do strings and like a comment and
boom it build a function and it actually
worked pretty well and it got me really
excited but I never thought that we will
get to the point we are today and
afterwards chatti PT came out and then
the rest is history like I started using
it for
so I'm a say data scientist I I have
very few experience with front end but
I've always tried to build front ends
for for internal apps like it's always
nice to have internal apps to look at
what whatever is happening with your
business but always use static htmls you
know this is interesting really because
if you're using something like copil
let's say you're someone who doesn't
know anything about front ends when you
using something like co-pilot you have
to be a little bit more surgical in
terms of when you declare what you want
sure say it in comment by comment say
look I want this and sometimes yeah you
could say give me a method that does
this but that's a that's even if you
don't know really what you're doing
around front end and I'm a backend
developer by trade so front ends yes
similar kind of aversion to front end
let's say so I I if if I was to go down
to that level I don't know what I would
ask for in in co-pilot or comments but
then when you take it up to a chat GPT
or we can talk a little bit about Claude
that you ask for bigger things yeah that
that's where I was going actually like
with the front end I I didn't use
co-pilot for the front end precisely for
what you were saying like you you're not
going to build a full web app you just
co-pilot you know if you do know front
end of course but if you don't know much
about it you really need full thing done
yeah so that's where I started using
chpt um it was not that bad actually it
was quite good but there was a lot of
back and forth and a lot of Googling
around because thing didn't work so we
just to Google around the errors and I
also used it a lot for building the
whole data infrastructure of predic my
my previous company I didn't know much
about infrastructure scodes actually
chhat PT was really good at building
awsm scripts for step functions Lambda
functions and API gate weights and stuff
like that that was I really felt
powerful it was really nice to do that
with chpt and that was amazing I
remember that's when I did that we we
started paying right away GI um chpt
plus to all of our employees oh my God
this is a huge productivity boost yeah
but I it was not yet at the point that
clot brought us which is I can actually
trust this to do a full flesh front end
and it will work you know let's let's
talk about that then because you did a
couple of projects right you did the one
project which was a a product colors
catalog and then a second product which
was a product match Explorer now both of
these you use Claude what was it that
drove you to Claude was it the model
itself providing you know a better level
of code return that you were expecting
was it the projects functionality was
the AI engineer what was the a what was
the the drive I I would say I don't know
like Twitter let's say
Twitter just social pressure even
pressure everybody's talking about it
but basically to make this short story
short I I gave a talk at AI thinkers
medene because I I really felt that some
people in the community were not using
llms from the API everybody's using
chachu PT but not everybody's using the
API to actually build products yeah so I
said okay I'm going to do a quick demo
so that people know how to call the API
and try to motivate people to do that
and that was a huge surprise for me
because I said okay's let's do this very
quick demo of how to extract colors from
shoes and it was I was happily surprised
that in one morning I managed to replace
a model that took us three or four
months to do with traditional machine
learning I did it with open AI in one
morning and it's way better yeah so that
really opened my eyes and I realized
like oh I think I'm
underutilizing CH to I was using it but
maybe not as much as I should so that
that started a journey okay what else
can I do yeah and I had been seeing
people around talking about coding with
differently not with co-pilot of course
but like full-fledged apps built
entirely from llms and I bumped into
Cloud engineer which is I think is a
great tool that was my first approach to
it which is this agent it's built by
this Italian guy Petro I think he called
he partnered up with an Tropic now to to
work on that and it was quite cool the
thing is that I I felt that it was
really powerful but I don't know as a
scientist myself I think I wanted to
touch the the equivalent of bare metal
in this case which is no I want to go
directly to the llm and me being the one
who who tests everything I wanted to
test the raw power of CLA so that's what
led me to different experiments where I
said I I'm going to force myself to use
the web UI yeah I'm not going to use any
extension in vs code that call CLA and
I'm going to document everything um
which it has advantages and disadvantage
when we think about the advantages yeah
you can get directly to Claude and you
can craft your prompts as you wish those
are the prompts that are going to yeah
Claude however you're not necessarily
seeing it in an IDE right you're still
seeing it a web UI so the experience
afterwards after Claude has created a
number of files which it stores in its
projects and things like that it's
something that you can't necessarily
then play with in an IDE
yeah yeah I think it was a painful
experience let's say yeah but again like
I really took it as an exercise as a
test I don't think that's the right way
of doing software nowadays like moving
forward I we use cursor or vs code we
continue that dep something like that
but it was really important for me to
take everything from the middle like I
want to go straight to the experience
and also backed by clot projects and
artifacts I I think it was a good setup
to to actually build my mindset develop
my own workflow you know that was
important for me and also that's why I'm
saying I took the scientist out of my
heart and said okay let's do some
Statistics over this so I use git to
document everything and in each Comet I
documented how many prompts I used how
many of those prompts were Corrections
over mistakes that the the llm did and
also I took note of this comet is
working on the back end on the front end
the data model scaffolding the project
so I did a full documentation these that
I will put on gith so that people can
take a look at it yeah let's describe
that let's describe what you faced with
in terms of the screen that that you
have for people who aren't familiar so
you obviously had a space to prompt you
had a and projects allow for a number of
files to be to be created and stored EX
for you you can use those various files
as as context and you can actually refer
to them right to say I want you to do X
taking Y and Z into account where y and
z are are two files maybe in the in the
yeah in terms of that flow what were
your requests talk us through the kind
of requests that you would make to
Claude what you would have as context
stored and then what you would do with
the output yeah so going let's go back a
bit on actually why we're here talking
you and me so when I started doing these
experiments that you described like
right after I finished my second one or
something like that I saw your first
podcast yeah and it really stroke me wow
they really put in words what I've been
feeling and mostly around the are we're
going for code Centric or product spec
Centric software development process so
and and that's important to to notice
like the product spec centering aspect
of it is quite important in the
experiment I was doing and I really felt
that the future of software developers
is going to increas become product
owners and Architects so I Tred in these
control experiments and actually it's
also worth saying that the experiment
that I did was something outside of
predicta yeah my company because I felt
it was important to start something from
scratch like how is cloth going to be
helpful for me if I start something from
scratch something that I don't have any
any PR prior knowledge so I did a a web
based version of Cards Against Humanity
that I call Cards Against AI uh but at
the end that's just details uh but to
get into the details of your question so
basically the CLA interface has what we
call projects is very simp it's a very
simple interface but extremely powerful
it's just like a nice ated environment
where you have like common chats that
they all belong to the same environment
you have a pseudo system prompt this is
the prompt the instructions for
everything that goes into these chats
and then let's say like a a folder where
you can just upload different files and
what's important there is that again
coming back to the fact that we become
product owners and Architects so those F
the instructions is like my my my
mindset as a product owner architect of
how I Envision the whole product and the
the files that you put into it is not
the code itself but product
specifications yeah natural language
product specifications and also
technical specifications like I don't
know like SQL ddl script to build a
database which is code also but
technical code that can serve as
technical specification the open API
schema definition and things like that
so that is the setup like an environment
that understands that you're trying to
build C Humanity you describe the text T
that you want to use the style of
interaction you want to have and that's
interesting the style of interaction
because this is this you're referring to
the roles I presume for this among other
things yeah like roles but also like the
main instructions for example something
I really like is to say provide mermaid
diagrams when relevance I see okay
because it's actually quite good at
coming up with abstractions of what it's
telling you putting them into mermaid
diagrams and with the artifact interface
which is basically inside a chat when
Cloud recognizes that it actually has
something that can be shown in a
different document we have a right pain
that previews the document so if it's a
mmory diagram you can see the code of
the mmory diagram but also you can see
the diagram right if it's react code you
can see the code but you you can also
see a rendering of the react visual yeah
yeah and and that's interesting that
rendering yeah it's effectively a reppel
in the clae project so it's not just
code that is being generated it's
actually running that in a local sandbox
it's a bit tricky
because in reality so sometimes like you
you create a react react visual that
tries to import components from other
files so it creates three different
files there's like an app that calls
component from other files but it
doesn't render so you have to cheat a
bit and force it to no no put all the
components on the same file so it's not
as powerful as rep but I I think you saw
recently I haven't tried it but rep they
they actually released an llm based yeah
Agent M I have to give it a try but I've
been on holidays for the past
month it's just crazy you stop for one
month and you're outdated on yeah You'
got about a year to catch up it yeah but
anyway that's my next thing to test yeah
so the conversations that you have
they're effectively you have it against
various roles so you might have it
against to start a conversation with a
front end specialist or a backend
Specialist or a data specialist and so
forth there's also CU I've seen
obviously the video that you presented
where you actually go through a lot of
this you talk about in that you talk a
little bit about firing roles
essentially so this is when a
conversation so talk this is where you
effectively get to a dead end with a
conversation and you need to start again
essentially talk tell us why you get to
that dead end and what the value of that
I think you mentioned handovers what the
value of a Handover is going from one to
the other so before going into that
maybe let's talk about roles first
because I think that's that we I think I
I skipped that part of the question and
I think it's important and that leads to
the dead end afterwards so I really felt
that what I was
doing it felt like each different chat
is as if I were talking to a different
software developer so when I was I think
we all agree up until this point we all
agree that you have to keep things sidy
and one conversation one subject you
cannot talk just open up a chat and
build the whole app in one chat mode and
projects provide with the environment
you can have different conversations M
so it's important to keep separate
conversations for separate subjects and
even when you're talking about backend
you can have several conversation about
backends and several conversation about
data models yeah and that's where I
think that the role of the software
developer is still relevant because we
know those abstraction layers and we
know what goes with what and we know the
glue points between the different roles
but basically the roles that I had like
the obvious ones which is backhand
developer software developer
on data engineer the CTO was The Meta
prompt let's say the data engineer was
actually quite good and I also had some
separate roles that served as Auditors
they cannot interact in between chats
but if I have one chat where I'm writing
front end specifications because the
whole project is not for writing the
code I use it also to write the
specifications of the project yeah so I
thought it was important that because as
we said at the
beginning products specifications is the
future so if that's the future clot
should help me write the product
specifications and that makes part of
the source Cod so you have prompts which
are short term which allow Claude to
create these longer term specs that then
it is able to then create the the code
from in with all of that information and
context in in that that's what I was
trying to achieve that's what I achieved
and those specifications I also added
them to the repository they're in G
they're committ to G and they're make
part of the statistics and just to
remind you 39% of the prompts 39% of the
prompts that I used were dedicated to
product specifications to to create the
spec the codes from so at the end you
for example I have a frontend developer
helping me write the specification the
front end then another one helping me a
backend developer helping me backend
specifications and then I had a full
stack developer where I said please read
front-end specifications backend
specifications let me know if there's
something wrong if there's consistency
what you should change I was quite
impressed with what it said like it said
listen you forgot this data model that
will be used in this part of frontting
for doing this and that and that was
actually quite powerful like before
actually implementing I used a lot of
critiques between the different
specifications did they actually get to
that did the developers get very
flustered when with their feedback and
they get they started speaking very
defensively towards that real life but
it's funny the way I describ this
auditor I actually described it as
colleague that you nobody likes but
useful you know like we all know what
we're talking about really good we don't
like you but thank you so that's the
description I gave to to that role and
going back to your question about firing
up these roles so let's talk about the
error rate I think it's important let's
develop about the error rate because I I
actually didn't fire him I fired myself
you have to be honest on that of course
I'm the one who made the mistakes yeah
so I did in total I did 169 prompts with
an error rate of
28% we can
and an error is describe an error I I
put a prompt yeah I say please make a
red button a a square red button M and
it makes I don't know like a diamond
blue button that's that so I know please
I said Square you'd need to you'd need
to fire that one straight that one stra
mean yeah for sure so that's an error
like I ask for something and it does
something that it's not in accordance to
what I asked and another error is
implement the front end yeah then I run
it and I bump into an error it doesn't
run MH for whatever reason so I have to
hey I got this error ites it didn't run
so that's an error but what I realized
is that most of those errors were due to
lack of clarity and we're circling back
to what we were saying like product
specifications are key clear product
specifications are key and I don't I
don't sadly I didn't take note of how
many of those Corrections were due to my
lack of specificity but I do have this
subjective feeling that most of them was
the case because and again the reason I
did cars Against Humanity instead of an
app for predicta is because I wanted to
bump into these cases yeah like I I
wanted to bump into the case where
specifications are not clear for me and
assume that's the new source code and
there you have the proof like most of
the errors I do have the feeling that I
was not specific enough I was going to
say what would you do next time then to
remove those errors is it be better
there's a really good there's a really
good quote actually goo goo had a
session with there's trainer of to come
and Dez said something I'm going to ruin
this quote now but Dez said something
along the lines of um like willingness
or or our wanting our need for short
prompting so to write short prompts is
robbing us of the ability to add
specificity to into into our requests so
effectively we can short prompts and get
something back from an llm quite easily
but it's actually the devils in the
detail as it were the the a lot of the
important information that we want to
get across to the llm we tend not to
sometimes just because a short prompt
will do is that kind of how you felt you
were interacting with Claude a little
bit giving not enough information for
the depth it needed to actually create
you something it wanted still stuff too
much in your mind and not enough on for
it so here's the thing I completely
agree with that but I have a a
bulletproof solution for that which is
in my instructions I say always ask for
clarifying questions so I can be lazy
yeah because I'm lazy and then Claud
realizes I'm being lazy and asks a lot
of clarifying questions y yeah that's
almost where you want a role yeah of
almost like we talk about Junior
developers a lot in in the podcasting in
with AI but almost a role where there's
a developer or someone who's constantly
asking clarification questions or depth
questions like okay I see what you're
asking for here but how or maybe there's
clarification on do you mean this or do
you mean that just add that level of
detail so that's a really nice
interaction where you know the lm's
prompting you effectively asking you to
add more detail it solves the blank page
problem yeah it's hard like it's
thinking is hard yeah and sometimes you
ask a friend to to be your sounding
board and it actually helps but in that
case my sounding board is fot and just
ask ask me as many questions as you can
and one thing we're going to ask a a
little bit about takeaways and things
like that but one thing sounds relevant
to to add it here is you mentioned as a
good takeaway you do less writing now in
terms of obviously code for sure but
probably possibly Less in in just
keyboard Taps anyway less writing but
more thinking yeah and that's really
interesting tell us a bit about that in
terms of what were the things you if you
were just to write start writing code
from scratch what would be the things
that you wouldn't think about up front
which an llm is actually forcing you or
making you think about earlier yeah so
let's put numbers on that yeah AI wrote
87% of the lines so that's a lot I only
wrote of code everything spefication
model so yeah much less writing but the
way I see it is I don't know let's
assume that you can put an IQ
requirement to every software
development test task and let's assume
that 80 90% of software development out
there is you don't have to be very
clever to to achieve that maybe between
it will require between 80 IQ an IQ of
80 on 110 120 I don't know how much that
is let's just assume that whatever just
for the purpose of illustration I feel
that with with Claud everything that
requires a lower IQ is immediately
automatized MH it's as simple as that
like the easy things that the things are
easy for you that is just mechanic
automatic like you're just you're typing
and you're not thinking all of that is
automatized the dull jobs that
developers tend not to want to do anyway
exactly that and that many developers
after 10 20 years they get bored and
they don't want to code anymore because
of that because all of the same thing
all of the same thing so all of things
like they go away quite quickly and
you're left with these high IQ
requirement task that you have to do so
that's why I think it well the
experiment really made me realize that
was tough yeah it was a tough exercise
it was really tough to to be thorough on
your description or another way of
saying it is my mind is a closed loop
like my messiness all of my messiness
inside they speak to each other and they
know how to speak to each other so if
it's only me who is coding I can let the
mess is be and things will happen the
code will be written but when you have a
second brain which is the llm you cannot
speak with messiness you have to put
your order on your head to make it clear
so that the instructions are clear
enough for that thing to handle their
own mess and write what you want to
write it's like teaching someone else or
education it's like when you realize
it's funny when you think you know a
topic and then you realize you have to
go and present at a conference about
this topic and you realize oh crap I
only know about 10% of this and then you
think about all the edge cases and it is
you need a it's breth and depth in terms
of what you know the extra you need in
order to actually be able to describe
that to someone else so that they can
actually get that good understanding and
and it's interesting to know where where
those gaps would be if you was to if you
was to not do that what would what were
some of the biggest surprises then that
you had while doing this was there some
around that lack of explicit context
that you were adding in the in in the
prompts and conversations were there
other surprises as you were going for me
the surpris
is I mean that I'm I love software
development but I I was not trained as a
software developer I I was trained I'm
I'm actually a mechanical engineer yeah
then I did my PhD in computer science
but that doesn't make you a computer
scientist that just makes you a PhD
let's say and all of my life I wanted to
become a software developer and I think
I became one as a data scientist you
have to do some software development I
actually became good at not being the
typical soft
data scientist that just do your
notebooks I do some back end I put
things in prodution it's okay but I
always felt like I cannot build a
product a full product I don't have the
capacity to to build a full product so
what surprised me the most is that
actually with this now I can and that
these models are powerful enough to help
me do a p and even an MVP buy a product
that people can pay for and for me that
was quite surprising and the fact that
you was clever enough to understand my
instructions he was clever enough to
compare front end and backend
specifications and come up with ideas
and what was it do you think because if
you to go just go to chat GPT plenty of
people would say this isn't good enough
to provide me with exactly what I need
to go to a market with or something like
that do you feel the structure of the
clae projects environment helped as well
or yeah I was going to that too there's
Claud as a model yeah that is more
powerful I would say but there's also
projects artifacts that okay it also
provides with for example for myself
where I don't know about front end so I
had the ability to iterate some visuals
in react with the artifacts before even
thinking about going to the terminal and
doing mpm run Dev or whatever I didn't
know how to run a ogs project at the
beginning but it doesn't matter with the
artifacts I can see the visual and then
I said okay I like that now help me
Implement everything and tell me how to
run this thing because I don't know so
yeah I think and I do think that
projects and artifacts are equally
important as a good llm yes yeah in my
case and when we talk about artifacts
and the stages that you have to go
through how does that differ to normal
software development in terms of you
talked about project specifications we
talked a little bit about the
architecture design and things like that
maybe some technical specifications
what's the or I guess when you sat down
to do it first of all how did you
approach it and would you do it today
differently yeah the way I approached it
again was I wanted to force myself to
only write prompts and only on the web
UI I wanted to be as close to the llm as
possible and avoid any other
interactions so that's how I did it how
I would do it for the next
project is I will still use the clot web
UI for specifications because I think
it's quite comfortable why use something
else like it's really really comfortable
with the artifacts you can see a marked
out document that is being written and
modified so that's comfortable enough
for the mockups is also very good so
maybe that's what I would use although I
also see that versil did a version of VC
something to build mockups maybe I will
give it a try to that yeah but when it
comes to code and implementing the code
itself one month ago I was saying that I
was going to try clot engineer but then
I took a look into cursor that they
released recently the composer mode that
I can actually do a comparable thing to
what I did in the web UI which is you
give an instruction and it gives you
several files and it actually modifies
several files or creates several files
I'm really curious to see how how that
goes yeah absolutely it does feel like
it's going to change the way workflows
can work what advice would you give to a
developer today wanting to implement
this type of new workflow I would say
first of all is change of mindset M like
I do think that as I said like all the
simple tasks are going to be automated
so we going to remain with the difficult
tasks and those difficult tasks they
require a different mindset like you
have to think as a product developer and
not as a software developer I think that
would be the the best advice I could
give so now to develop further and what
I mean by that is that now
implementation the code is just
implementation
and starts becoming less relevant I I've
been a hardcore python for my whole life
now I'm considering maybe I will do no
GS I don't care yeah will impation yeah
just an implementation even the cars
Against Humanity I did the backhand in
Python and I was thinking doesn't make
sense if if the front end is in ogs I
would just to the back end in the same
service so things like that switch your
mind from code matters but not as much
as before proper code does matter and
you have to be the auditor of the
process so that code is actually good
don't trust blindly I don't think we're
ready to trust LMS blindly at the moment
but it becomes just an implementation
detail so really focus your mind as a
product developer care about why you're
doing what you're doing who is going to
use this who is going to be the end user
care about the user experience the UI
and broaden your spectrum I think that I
do have a feeling that but I don't know
if it it will still make sense to be a
backend developer front end developer I
think we will have a broader base of
knowledge in all disciplines of of
software development and maybe we will
still have specialities maybe we'll
still have backend developers and front
end developers but you cannot just be
that yeah I think that's interesting
developers will effectively be more
holistic yeah and I guess that lead that
lends itself to the architecture style
of looking at thinking the application
as a whole and recognizing more ically
flows that go all the way through from a
user to a back end or something now I I
have to give some Nuance to my advice
because I think it's important I'm
talking as a recent entrepreneur I had
my startup I'm thinking about somebody
that wants to build products an early
stage startups I don't know if
enterprise software developers should
follow my advice maybe yes maybe not I
don't know I'm not sure yeah I guess
it's different if you're if you're
building something from scratch claw
doesn't have to look and already know
about a huge existing system which would
be a lot of context and I think that's
definitely a trickier but if we're
talking about startup concept yeah I
think that's the one like become
Architects become product product owners
I'm really worried about it I think that
us that were raised in this era where we
actually had to write code we are lucky
enough to go through that because we
will be able to audit the code but what
about the newer Generations I'm really
worried about that list going to be an
interesting transition as well because
you mentioned I think it was 87% of of
87% yeah 87% of anything generated was
generated by an llm so apart from your
prompts 87% generated by the llm the
rest was added by you whether it's
specifications or code Etc and you did
do a little bit of coding how do you see
that balance between human coding the
need for humans to code write code and
the need for humans to effectively drive
an llm to write code or write some
implementation how do you see that
balance changing over a year or two five
years 10 years so killer question of
asking a a 10 year out question about
what the future's going to be with a I
apologize for that don't worry it's
funny because I feel that we live we all
I think we can all agree on that that
the future became a real really weird
concept yeah the future can be tomorrow
two weeks months and also when you talk
about when you talk with some people you
feel that they are living in the past
yeah like I have this feeling when I
speak to software developers that they
are not using chat GPT or code assistant
are you living in the past what is
happening so it's like weird because at
the moment people are living in the past
in the present and have the future right
here in your nose so what is that future
for me that future immediately is I
think for as long as my mind works I
want to continue Building Products yeah
like maybe not coding build building
products but right away immediately I
don't think llms are good enough to the
point that we don't need to code anymore
I think we still need to code I I I do
dream of a world where even though I
love coding I think it would be
beautiful if we can just build products
out of product specifications not
prompts I don't like the word prompts I
like it but it's too generic it's like
saying English English is too generic
what do you mean is it an essay is it an
email is it you see so I would say
product specification not promps
potentially using prompts to maybe
generate those speciations or help what
you did
the product specification is what will
matter I think that's the case natural
language product specifications that you
can use an llm to help you write them
like the page problem like ask me
questions about this idea that I have at
the end you will get to it it's okay but
natural language specifications but also
technical specifications like API open
API schemas and stuff like that
tests and the advantage that we have is
that code is verifiable yeah
so if we have good specification and
good tests I think we can get to that
point yeah awesome I don't know when but
I hope we'll see it won't be it won't be
long see amazing Filipe thank you very
much and appreciate you coming to London
in person for it's been great chatting
actually in the office for the last
couple of days and great to be able to
do this podcast in in person thanks for
having me it's been really fun Absolut
pleasure thank you and right after this
on YouTube we're going to hands on we're
going to show Claude 35 with your
project set up show the git flows the
ability to create specification to
generate code using the methodologies
and the workflows that we just talked
about so do look out for that and thank
you for the listeners for tuning in and
hope to tune in again
[Applause]
soon thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by tessla
[Applause]
[Music]